<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Julia | David Leather</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/julia/</link>
      <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/julia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Julia</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/media/icon_hu_645fa481986063ef.png</url>
      <title>Julia</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/julia/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>QuadraticKalman.jl</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/project/quadratickalman/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/project/quadratickalman/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;QuadraticKalman.jl&lt;/strong&gt; is a Julia package for nonlinear state estimation using quadratic approximations of the Kalman filter. It extends traditional Kalman filtering techniques to handle nonlinearity in dynamic systems, making it a powerful tool for applications in finance, engineering, and scientific computing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;features&#34;&gt;Features&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quadratic Kalman Filtering:&lt;/strong&gt; Implements second-order approximations for improved accuracy in nonlinear state estimation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Flexible Model Specification:&lt;/strong&gt; Supports user-defined state-space models with nonlinear dynamics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Efficient Computation:&lt;/strong&gt; Leverages Julia’s speed and automatic differentiation to compute gradients and Hessians efficiently.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time-Series Applications:&lt;/strong&gt; Suitable for filtering, smoothing, and forecasting in econometrics, engineering, and physics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Modular and Extendable:&lt;/strong&gt; Designed with flexibility in mind to allow easy adaptation to domain-specific problems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-quadratickalmanjl&#34;&gt;Why QuadraticKalman.jl?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike standard Extended Kalman Filters (EKF) or Unscented Kalman Filters (UKF), QuadraticKalman.jl captures higher-order dynamics without relying on sample-based approximations. This results in more accurate state estimates for highly nonlinear processes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;use-cases&#34;&gt;Use Cases&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Financial Modeling:&lt;/strong&gt; Estimating latent factors in asset pricing and risk modeling.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Engineering Systems:&lt;/strong&gt; Sensor fusion, robotics, and control applications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Climate and Environmental Science:&lt;/strong&gt; Data assimilation for geophysical models.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Neuroscience &amp;amp; Biomedicine:&lt;/strong&gt; Tracking hidden states in neural or physiological data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;about-the-developer&#34;&gt;About the Developer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;QuadraticKalman.jl is developed by &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dleather&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;David Leather&lt;/a&gt;, a finance professor and quantitative researcher with expertise in econometrics, machine learning, and nonlinear state-space modeling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🔗 &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dleather/QuadraticKalman.jl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;GitHub Repository&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
